Now, for the techniques that was commonly used by the detectors that was indicator removal
clearing the even logs from the machine, we all know where the even logs get saved, see
even though system dirty divinity and we can find a lot of logs there, application system
security logs.
So, these logs are all the clear evidence of the attack, how the attack was happening
or happened and what was the IP and it will clearly show the IOS is, so how the detector
enters into the machine, so which IP they have used and which user they have compromised,
ok.
So, even the EDR platforms using this kind of logs to grip the output based on the query
what we are giving, ok.
The EDRs will bring it the logs from this EBTX even logs and it will be giving a proper
result to the analyst who is investigating the activity or an incident.
So, we all know where the even logs can be saved, so if you go for this, there is this,
we are going to restart my machine, yeah now the machine already, so let us get the machine
out, it is open, the EBTX what we need, yeah, so, so in security even logs you can find
there is 30,000, 0 to 9 events more than 30,000 events and setup logs, we have plenty of events
right, event system logs contain 1000, 170, 172 events, so clearing this event logs will
be very, very simple, ok, so let us clear out the security even logs from the machine,
so the command is pretty simple, you need your command line interface will be in administrator
mode, so this is the one of the login web tool, so you can, we can, we can use this web
tool to clear the even logs from the machine, ok, so let me, WVQT web tool, CL, CL means
clear, you can use security, so now it will get executed and let me refresh the, refresh
the logs, so now we can find 30,000 logs changed to 6, right, so everything gone from
the machine, so here we have 173, 173,000, 1733 events, we can use the same similar
command like SYSTEM system, ok, so now let me refresh the system here, so here you can
find there is a two events, so this is how the protectors will be clearing the evidence
from the machine, ok, so if you are foreign secating the machine and you need some kind
of even logs to foreign, foreign secate, right, if you, if you need a credential access
privilege escalation or something something, you need some kind of evidence to investigate,
but they are clearing the evidence from the machine, so this will be really, really difficult
to understand what happened actually inside the machine, ok, yeah, so this is the scenario
how the protectors will be acting in the backend, so exactly you can, you can see the
similar command when you are doing an investigation, investigation about this kind of activity,
so let's hop off from here and we will continue our discussion in the next video, see
you guys, bye bye.